

hasnichandrahasan@gmail.com



176B/24, Near Hill Bunk, Opposite Ooty Residency, Club Road, Ooty-643001



CHANDRAHASAN

HR recruiter | Content writer



EDUCATION

2017-2019

SNS College of Technology, Coimbatore MBA-HR and Finance Anna University Chennai with 9.6 CGPA (No history of arrear)

2011-2015

CSI College of Engineering, Ketti B.E-Electrical and Electronics Engineering Anna University Chennai with 7.89 CGPA (No history of arrear)

2009-2011

Bethlehem Girls Higher Secondary School, Ooty

HSC, State Board, with 84%

2009

Nazareth Convent Girls High School, Ooty SSLC, ICSE Board, with 86%

PERSONAL SKILLS

- ✓ Good communication verbal as well as written.
- Excellent conceptual and analytical skills.
- ✓ Effective interpersonal and negotiation skills.
- ✓ Strong leadership skills.
- ✓ Ability to work as individual as well as in group.
- ✓ Time management.

TECHNICAL SKIL

MS-Word, Excel, PowerPoint

Tally ERP 9

Recruiting

Screening

Sourcing

Cold calling

Training & Development

Statutory Compliance

Pivot table and Power query

Copy editing

Language editing

Proof reading

Content writing

Copy editing trainee

TNQ Books and Journals, Coimbatore March 2017- August 2017

- Proofread text and correct spelling, grammar, and punctuation errors.
- Checked text to ensure it is well written and logically structured.
- Verified factual correctness of information, such as dates and statistics.
- Checked text for style, readability, and adherence to editorial policies.
- Checked facts and raised queries with the author.

PROFILE SUMMARY

HR Recruiter having experience in hiring and onboarding candidates, performance tracking and maintaining HR records. Reliable, knowledgeable and highly organized team player with excellent communication skills, team building and relationship management. Highly creative and industrious content developer. Experienced in creating engaging content. Conducts detailed research and adept at compiling information.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Content Developer and Language editor

AGK Research (IJAICT India Publications), Coimbatore October 2020- March 2021

- Developed technical content for journal publishing.
- Proofreading content for errors and inconsistencies.
- Editing and polishing existing content to improve readability.
- Creating compelling headlines and body copy that will capture the attention of the target audience.

HR Recruiter

Craskills learning solutions, Coimbatore April 2019-March 2020

- Involved in full recruiting life cycle & end to end recruitment.
- Identifying vacancies and posting job opening in job portals.
- Sourcing resume from various Job Portals i.e. Naukri, Indeed, CV Box and networking tools such as LinkedIn.
- Screening resumes and matching applicant with open positions.
- Speaking/Emailing to the screened resumes and checking their availability and interests.
- Making Cold calls and also conducted onsite interviews for candidates to check the candidate's suitability for the position.
- Communicated the duties, compensation, benefits and working conditions to all potential candidates.
- Sell and forward the interested candidate resumes to clients against requirements.
- Assessing the availability of hiring team leaders and cross checking that against the availability of candidates.
- Onboarding process and issued offer letter for employees.
- Placed 20+ employees at companies for the position of telecallers and BDE.

CERTIFICATIONS

Recruitment (Core HR)

Craskills learning solutions, Coimbatore

Tally ERP 9
Venus Infotech, Ooty

A C H I E V E M E N T S AND AWARDS

Academic Excellence Award / SNS College of Technology

Best Outgoing Student Award / SNS College of Technology

Behind the Scenes Wonder Award / SNS College of Technology

Students Association President of EEE Department / CSI College of Engineering

Executive Member of EEE Department / CSI College of Engineering

LANGUAGES

English Tamil Hindi



- Arranged page layouts of photos, articles, and advertisements.
- Rewritten the text to improve clarity and readability

Admin

Venus InfoTech, Ooty
December 2015- December 2016

- Maintain internal databases and submit expense reports.
- Maintain employee records.
- Maintain a filing system for data on customers and external partners.
- Prepare regular reports and presentations.
- Organize, store and print company documents as needed.
- Answer and redirect phone calls.
- Carrying out clerical duties such as answering phone calls, responding to emails, and preparing documents, including office correspondence, memos, resumes, and presentations.
- Maintaining general office files, including job files, vendor files, and other files.

INTERNSHIPS

HR Trainee

Ammarun Foundries, Coimbatore January 2019-April 2019

- Assisting departments with their recruitment needs.
- Piloted study on Quality of work life of employees and recorded the feedback.
- Recording, maintaining and monitoring attendance.
- Maintaining and regularly updating master database (personal file, personal database) of each employee
- Submitting daily or periodical work progress reports to Assistant HRM.
- Assisting and coordinating in employee engagement activities.
- Developed new KPI parameters for employee positions and monitored it.

HR Intern

Emerald Jewel Industry India Ltd., Coimbatore June 2018 - July 2018

- Coordination of applicants, conduction of psychometric test, interview.
- Conducted induction and motivation classes for new joiners.
- Filling missing OT details of employees in database.
- To verify the attendance of employee and calculate loss of pay statement based on the existing attendance rules using software named SPINE HR and VISUAL BASIC.

(C.HASNI)